1:"$Sreact.fragment"
2:I[7555,[],""]
3:I[1295,[],""]
4:I[9742,["177","static/chunks/app/layout-7d8a5f63f536cdcf.js"],"Analytics"]
6:I[9665,[],"OutletBoundary"]
9:I[9665,[],"ViewportBoundary"]
b:I[9665,[],"MetadataBoundary"]
d:I[6614,[],""]
:HL["/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/31d717072bdb6d85.css","style"]
:HL["/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/93628e14bbee05a5.css","style"]
0:{"P":null,"b":"yCqRTNLEPBdkYbRRbuCZd","p":"/dva-c02-quiz-app","c":["","quiz","aws-developer-4540360",""],"i":false,"f":[[["",{"children":["quiz",{"children":[["id","aws-developer-4540360","d"],{"children":["__PAGE__",{}]}]}]},"$undefined","$undefined",true],["",["$","$1","c",{"children":[[["$","link","0",{"rel":"stylesheet","href":"/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/31d717072bdb6d85.css","precedence":"next","crossOrigin":"$undefined","nonce":"$undefined"}],["$","link","1",{"rel":"stylesheet","href":"/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/93628e14bbee05a5.css","precedence":"next","crossOrigin":"$undefined","nonce":"$undefined"}]],["$","html",null,{"lang":"en","children":["$","body",null,{"className":"font-sans __variable_1f39b6 __variable_c20681","children":[["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":[[["$","title",null,{"children":"404: This page could not be found."}],["$","div",null,{"style":{"fontFamily":"system-ui,\"Segoe UI\",Roboto,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif,\"Apple Color Emoji\",\"Segoe UI Emoji\"","height":"100vh","textAlign":"center","display":"flex","flexDirection":"column","alignItems":"center","justifyContent":"center"},"children":["$","div",null,{"children":[["$","style",null,{"dangerouslySetInnerHTML":{"__html":"body{color:#000;background:#fff;margin:0}.next-error-h1{border-right:1px solid rgba(0,0,0,.3)}@media (prefers-color-scheme:dark){body{color:#fff;background:#000}.next-error-h1{border-right:1px solid rgba(255,255,255,.3)}}"}}],["$","h1",null,{"className":"next-error-h1","style":{"display":"inline-block","margin":"0 20px 0 0","padding":"0 23px 0 0","fontSize":24,"fontWeight":500,"verticalAlign":"top","lineHeight":"49px"},"children":404}],["$","div",null,{"style":{"display":"inline-block"},"children":["$","h2",null,{"style":{"fontSize":14,"fontWeight":400,"lineHeight":"49px","margin":0},"children":"This page could not be found."}]}]]}]}]],[]],"forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}],["$","$L4",null,{}]]}]}]]}],{"children":["quiz",["$","$1","c",{"children":[null,["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":"$undefined","forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}]]}],{"children":[["id","aws-developer-4540360","d"],["$","$1","c",{"children":[null,["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":"$undefined","forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}]]}],{"children":["__PAGE__",["$","$1","c",{"children":["$L5","$undefined",null,["$","$L6",null,{"children":["$L7","$L8",null]}]]}],{},null,false]},null,false]},null,false]},null,false],["$","$1","h",{"children":[null,["$","$1","cO7l6Diwn8A2Fb9ODqzP_",{"children":[["$","$L9",null,{"children":"$La"}],null]}],["$","$Lb",null,{"children":"$Lc"}]]}],false]],"m":"$undefined","G":["$d","$undefined"],"s":false,"S":true}
e:I[1184,["261","static/chunks/261-2d9b76ccba401937.js","200","static/chunks/app/quiz/%5Bid%5D/page-d7cb26530e4508b3.js"],"default"]
5:["$","$Le",null,{"quiz":{"id":"aws-developer-4540360","title":"Practice Test #2 (AWS Certified Developer Associate - DVA-C02)","description":"Practice questions for AWS Developer Associate (DVA-C02) exam â€” covering core AWS services like SQS, Lambda, DynamoDB, and more.","questions":[{"question":"You are looking to deploy applications a fleet of on-premise instances, with precise blue/green strategy. You want full control over the deployment steps and the possibility to add hooks. Which service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"CodeDeploy","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodeBuild","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodePipeline","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS CodeDeploy is a deployment service that automates application deployments to Amazon EC2 instances, on-premises instances, or serverless Lambda functions.During a blue/green deployment, the latest application revision is installed on replacement instances, and traffic is rerouted to these instances when you choose, either immediately or as soon as you are done testing the new environment.You can launch and track the status of your deployments through the AWS CodeDeploy console or the AWS CLI. You receive a report that lists when each application revision was deployed and to which Amazon EC2 instances. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/welcome.html"},{"question":"You have a deployed a Lambda functions written in Golang that has loaded the X-Ray SDK. The IAM permissions of the Lambda function do allow you to send data to X-Ray. But things still don't work, what's a likely source of the problem?","answers":[{"text":"Lambda X-Ray active tracing must be enabled","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The IAM permissions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Authorise Lambda source in the X-Ray console","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The X-Ray agent must be loaded with the code","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"If your Lambda function runs on a schedule, or is invoked by a service that is not instrumented, you can configure Lambda to sample and record invocations with active tracing.Readf morehttps://docs.aws.amazon.com/xray/latest/devguide/xray-services-lambda.html"},{"question":"We need to perform 10 strongly consistent reads per second of 6KB each. How many RCU do we need?","answers":[{"text":"20","isCorrect":true},{"text":"60","isCorrect":false},{"text":"30","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"One read capacity unit represents one strongly consistent read per second for an item up to 4 KB in size. If you need to read an item that is larger than 4 KB, DynamoDB will need to consume additional read capacity units. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/HowItWorks.ProvisionedThroughput.html"},{"question":"You are trying to upload an object of 500GB of size, but the upload is failing with an error message indicating the file is too big. What's the problem?","answers":[{"text":"You need to use multi-part upload for large files","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The maximum file size is 5 GB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your IAM permissions are incorrect","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need to place a service limit request increase with AWS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"In general, when your object size reaches 100 MB, you should consider using multipart uploads instead of uploading the object in a single operation. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/uploadobjusingmpu.html"},{"question":"Which of the following can be used to implement a REST API? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"ALB + ECS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"API Gateway + Lambda","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SES + S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch + CloudFront","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EBS + RDS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/getting-started/projects/build-serverless-web-app-lambda-apigateway-s3-dynamodb-cognito/module-4/ https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/microservice-delivery-with-amazon-ecs-and-application-load-balancers/"},{"question":"Which of the following statements isn't true for SNS?","answers":[{"text":"SNS Messages can be retrieved at a later date","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Messages are sent to all subscribers","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lambda can be a target of SNS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SQS can be a target of SNS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) is a highly available, durable, secure, fully managed pub/sub messaging service that enables you to decouple microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications. Amazon SNS provides topics for high-throughput, push-based, many-to-many messaging. Using Amazon SNS topics, your publisher systems can fan out messages to a large number of subscriber endpoints for parallel processing, including Amazon SQS queues, AWS Lambda functions, and HTTP/S webhooks. Additionally, SNS can be used to fan out notifications to end users using mobile push, SMS, and email.  Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/sns/"},{"question":"Each ECS Task must have an IAM policy attached to it. How do you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"Create an IAM Role for ECS and assign it to the tasks","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Assign an IAM role to the EC2 instance","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Load the credentials within the docker container","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use the parameter store to pass in AWS credentials","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You must also create a role for your tasks to use before you can specify it in your task definitions. You can create the role using the Amazon Elastic Container Service Task Role service role in the IAM console. Then you can attach your specific IAM policy to the role that gives the containers in your task the permissions you desire. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECS/latest/developerguide/task-iam-roles.html"},{"question":"You would like each of your API Gateway stages (dev, test, prod) to point to a specific Lambda function version. Which mechanism would you need to use? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"Stage Variables","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Lambda Aliases","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Lambda Versions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lambda X-Ray integration","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mapping Templates","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Stage variables are name-value pairs that you can define as configuration attributes associated with a deployment stage of an API. They act like environment variables and can be used in your API setup and mapping templates.With deployment stages in API Gateway, you can manage multiple release stages for each API, such as alpha, beta, and production. Using stage variables you can configure an API deployment stage to interact with different backend endpoints. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/stage-variables.html"},{"question":"While you send messages one by one to Kinesis Stream, you are getting a ProvisionedThroughputException. How can you improve the situation while keeping cost constant? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"Batch messages","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use Exponential Backoff","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Increase the number of shards","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Decrease the Stream retention duration","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"To reduce overhead and increase throughput, the application produce records in batches.  Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/big-data/implementing-efficient-and-reliable-producers-with-the-amazon-kinesis-producer-library/"},{"question":"You are currently storing 500 GB of data on your S3 bucket \"my-corp\". What's the maximum total volume of data that your S3 bucket can contain?","answers":[{"text":"unlimited","isCorrect":true},{"text":"10 TB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"25 TB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"5 TB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The total volume of data and number of objects you can store are unlimited. Individual Amazon S3 objects can range in size from a minimum of 0 bytes to a maximum of 5 terabytes. The largest object that can be uploaded in a single PUT is 5 gigabytes. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/s3/faqs/"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a valid CloudFormation Parameter Type?","answers":[{"text":"DependentParameter","isCorrect":true},{"text":"String","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CommaDelimitedList","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS::EC2::KeyPair::KeyName","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/parameters-section-structure.html"},{"question":"What's the best practice regarding accessing the AWS Root account?","answers":[{"text":"It should be accessible by one admin only after enabling Multi-factor authentication","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It should be accessible by 3 to 6 members of the IT team","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It should be accessible using the access_key_id and secret_access_key_id","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It should be accessible by no one, throw away the passwords after creating the account","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"If you continue to use the root user credentials, we recommend that you follow the security best practice to enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) for your account. Because your root user can perform sensitive operations in your account, adding an additional layer of authentication helps you to better secure your account. Multiple types of MFA are available. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/id_root-user.html#id_root-user_manage_mfa"},{"question":"Which key does allow you to expose outputs to other CloudFormation stacks?","answers":[{"text":"Export","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Expose","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Output","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Import","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"To export a stack's output value, use the Export field in the Output section of the stack's template. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/using-cfn-stack-exports.html"},{"question":"Your application deployed to Elastic Beanstalk from CodePipeline (CodeCommit => CodeBuild) takes a very long time to be deployed due to the fact it has to resolve many dependencies on each of your 100 target EC2 instances. What do you suggest to improve the performance while having the minimal amount of code and developer impact?","answers":[{"text":"Bundle the dependencies in the source code during the last stage of CodeBuild","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Bundle the dependencies in the source code in CodeCommit","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Store the dependencies in S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Create a custom platform for Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Bundling the dependencies with the code during the build output phase is a great way to speed up Beanstalk deployments"},{"question":"You would like to audit the actual usage of your KMS key. Which service can help you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":true},{"text":"VPC Flow Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"KMS policies","isCorrect":false},{"text":"IAM","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudTrail provides event history of your AWS account activity, including actions taken through the AWS Management Console, AWS SDKs, command line tools, and other AWS services. This event history simplifies security analysis, resource change tracking, and troubleshooting. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is correct for CloudFormation?","answers":[{"text":"The order in which resources are created must not be specified","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CloudFormation templates are static and do not allow parameters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudFormation templates can only be valid for one region and account","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudFormation templates lock the configuration of the created resources","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudFormation is declarative, not imperative Read more:  https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/cfn-whatis-concepts.html"},{"question":"You would like to add hooks to your AWS CodeDeploy deployment. How can you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"define a .appspec file in the root directory","isCorrect":true},{"text":"define a .buildspec file in the root directory","isCorrect":false},{"text":"define a .buildspec file in the codebuild/ directory","isCorrect":false},{"text":"define a .appspec file in the codebuild/ directory","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"An AppSpec file must be a YAML-formatted file named appspec.yml and it must be placed in the root of the directory structure of an application's source code. Otherwise, deployments fail. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/reference-appspec-file.html"},{"question":"You would like to improve the CPU and network performance of your Lambda functions without changing your code. How should you do it?","answers":[{"text":"Increase the RAM assigned to your function","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Increase the instance type for your functions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Change your function runtime to use Golang","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Increase the timeout","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Specify the amount of memory you want to allocate for your Lambda function. AWS Lambda allocates CPU power proportional to the memory by using the same ratio as a general purpose Amazon EC2 instance type, such as an M3 type. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/resource-model.html"},{"question":"You are hosting a public AWS website on S3 bucket but every user is currently getting a 403 (Forbidden) error. How can you remedy this error?","answers":[{"text":"Create a bucket policy","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Create an IAM role","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Enable CORS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Enable Encrytion","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Bucket policy is an access policy option available for you to grant permission to your Amazon S3 resources. It uses JSON-based access policy language.  Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/example-bucket-policies.html"},{"question":"Which ECS config must you enable to allow your ECS tasks to endorse IAM roles?","answers":[{"text":"ECS_ENABLE_TASK_IAM_ROLE","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ECS_AVAILABLE_LOGGING_DRIVERS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ECS_ENGINE_AUTH_DATA","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ECS_CLUSTER","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"ECS_ENABLE_TASK_IAM_ROLE=trueEnables IAM roles for tasks for containers with the bridge and default network modes. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECS/latest/developerguide/task-iam-roles.html#enable_task_iam_roles"},{"question":"How can you retrieve a nested JSON attribute in your DynamoDB query?","answers":[{"text":"Specify a ProjectionExpression","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use a FilterExpression","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use the --query parameter","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"A projection expression is a string that identifies the attributes you want. To retrieve a single attribute, specify its name. For multiple attributes, the names must be comma-separated. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/Expressions.ProjectionExpressions.html"},{"question":"What isn't a target sink for Kinesis Firehose?","answers":[{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":true},{"text":"S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Redshift","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElasticSearch","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose is the easiest way to load streaming data into data stores and analytics tools. It can capture, transform, and load streaming data into Amazon S3, Amazon Redshift, Amazon Elasticsearch Service, and Splunk. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-firehose/faqs/"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a valid CloudFormation section?","answers":[{"text":"Groups","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Parameters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mappings","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Metadata","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/template-anatomy.html"},{"question":"You want to perform a slow rollout of a new API version using API Gateway. Which feature should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Canary Deployment","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Stage Variables","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mapping Templates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Custom Authorizers","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"In a canary release deployment, total API traffic is separated at random into a production release and a canary release with a pre-configured ratio. Typically, the canary release receives a small percentage of API traffic and the production release takes up the rest. The updated API features are only visible to API traffic through the canary. You can adjust the canary traffic percentage to optimize test coverage or performance. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/canary-release.html"},{"question":"We need to write 6 objects per second of 4.5 KB each in DynamoDB. What's the target WCU?","answers":[{"text":"30","isCorrect":true},{"text":"24","isCorrect":false},{"text":"15","isCorrect":false},{"text":"46","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"One write capacity unit represents one write per second for an item up to 1 KB in size. If you need to write an item that is larger than 1 KB, DynamoDB will need to consume additional write capacity units. The total number of write capacity units required depends on the item size. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/HowItWorks.ProvisionedThroughput.html"},{"question":"You would like to build a serverless REST API. Which technology combo will you choose?","answers":[{"text":"API Gateway + Lambda","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ELB + EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ALB + ECS on EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Route 53 + EC2","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/getting-started/projects/build-serverless-web-app-lambda-apigateway-s3-dynamodb-cognito/module-4/"},{"question":"When you rollback a CodeDeploy, where is the application deployed first?","answers":[{"text":"To the failed instances","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To the non-failed instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To new instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You cannot rollback CodeDeploy","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS CodeDeploy rolls back deployments by redeploying a previously deployed revision of an application as a new deployment on the failed instances. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/deployments-rollback-and-redeploy.html"},{"question":"What do you need to do to ensure your Kinesis Stream can scale? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"The partition key must take a great number of different values","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You need to add shards","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You need to enable auto-scale","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The partition key must only take few values","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Kinesis Data Streams segregates the data records belonging to a stream into multiple shards. It uses the partition key that is associated with each data record to determine which shard a given data record belongs to. Partition keys are Unicode strings with a maximum length limit of 256 bytes.A stream is composed of one or more shards, each of which provides a fixed unit of capacity. Each shard can support up to 5 transactions per second for reads, up to a maximum total data read rate of 2 MB per second and up to 1,000 records per second for writes, up to a maximum total data write rate of 1 MB per second (including partition keys). The data capacity of your stream is a function of the number of shards that you specify for the stream. The total capacity of the stream is the sum of the capacities of its shards. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/streams/latest/dev/key-concepts.html"},{"question":"Your company does want S3 server side encryption but want to be able to provide the encryption key. Which encryption mechanism suits best?","answers":[{"text":"SSE-C","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SSE-KMS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Client Side Encryption","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SSE-S3","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Use Server-Side Encryption with Customer-Provided Keys (SSE-C)   : You manage the encryption keys and Amazon S3 manages the encryption, as it writes to disks, and decryption, when you access your objects. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/UsingEncryption.html"},{"question":"Your application load balancer cannot connect to your EC2 instance, it experiences a timeout. What's the problem?","answers":[{"text":"Security Groups","isCorrect":true},{"text":"IAM Roles","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The application is down","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The ALB is warming up","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Check your security group rules of your EC2 instance. You need a security group rule that allows inbound traffic from your public IPv4 address on the proper port. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/TroubleshootingInstancesConnecting.html#TroubleshootingInstancesConnectionTimeout"},{"question":"You would like to see the logs of your failed CodeBuilds. How should you do it?","answers":[{"text":"Enable S3 and CloudWatch integration","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use AWS Lambda integration","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use CloudWatch Events","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use Kinesis","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"If there is any build output, the build environment uploads its output to an Amazon S3 bucket.While the build is running, you can use the AWS CodeBuild console, AWS CLI, or AWS SDKs, to get summarized build information from AWS CodeBuild and detailed build information from Amazon CloudWatch Logs. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/concepts.html"},{"question":"Do you have to provision EC2 instances in order for CodePipeline to be able to run?","answers":[{"text":"no","isCorrect":true},{"text":"yes","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CodePipeline is a serverless managed service"},{"question":"You would like to deploy a database that has the capability to perform joins and fast per-row OLTP processing. Which database technology is best?","answers":[{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Redshift","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) makes it easy to set up, operate, and scale a relational database in the cloud. Amazon RDS supports the most demanding database applications. You can choose between two SSD-backed storage options: one optimized for high-performance OLTP applications, and the other for cost-effective general-purpose use. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/rds/"},{"question":"You want to have full control over the deployment of your Elastic Beanstalk application and control the portion of the traffic that will go to your new application version, so that you can perform extended testing. When the time is right, you want a simple way to switch the environment for the end users. Which deployment mechanism fits best?","answers":[{"text":"blue/green","isCorrect":true},{"text":"rolling","isCorrect":false},{"text":"immutable","isCorrect":false},{"text":"all at once","isCorrect":false},{"text":"rolling with additional batches","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"As AWS Elastic Beanstalk performs an in-place update when you update your application versions, your application can become unavailable to users for a short period of time. You can avoid this downtime by performing a blue/green deployment, where you deploy the new version to a separate environment, and then swap CNAMEs of the two environments to redirect traffic to the new version at what ever point you want the traffic to be comepeletly redirected to the new environment. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.rolling-version-deploy.html https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.deploy-existing-version.html"},{"question":"You would like to see a list of the API calls performed by your CodePipeline pipeline. Which service will help you with that?","answers":[{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodePipeline Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"IAM","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch Logs","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudTrail provides event history of your AWS account activity, including actions taken through the AWS Management Console, AWS SDKs, command line tools, and other AWS services. This event history simplifies security analysis, resource change tracking, and troubleshooting. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/"},{"question":"You would like to pass 1 MB of encrypted data to your AWS Lambda function, that it needs to load before properly functioning. Which method will work best?","answers":[{"text":"Envelope Encrption and store as file within the code","isCorrect":true},{"text":"KMS direct encryption and store as file","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Envelope Encryption and store as environment variable","isCorrect":false},{"text":"KMS Encryption and store as environment variable","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS Lambda environment variables have a maximum size of a few KB. Additionally, the direct \"Encrypt\" API of KMS also has a few KB limit. To encrypt 1 MB, you need to use the Encryption SDK and pack the encrypted file with the lambda function.  Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/encryption-sdk/latest/developer-guide/introduction.html"},{"question":"What is the maximum number of messages than can be stored in a SQS queue?","answers":[{"text":"no limit","isCorrect":true},{"text":"10000","isCorrect":false},{"text":"100000","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10000000","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"There are no message limits for storing in SQS, but \"in flight messages\" do have limits. Make sure to delete messages after you have processed them. Read more:  https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSSimpleQueueService/latest/SQSDeveloperGuide/sqs-limits.html "},{"question":"You need to store data that needs to be available on a tablet, a mobile device and a web application for the same user. Which product allows you to achieve this?","answers":[{"text":"Cognito Sync","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cognito Identity Pools","isCorrect":false},{"text":"S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EFS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Cognito Sync is an AWS service and client library that enables cross-device syncing of application-related user data. You can use it to synchronize user profile data across mobile devices and the web without requiring your own backend. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cognito/latest/developerguide/cognito-sync.html"},{"question":"You have SSH into your EC2 instance. How can you check if it can terminate other EC2 instances without actually terminating them?","answers":[{"text":"Use the AWS CLI --dry-run option","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use the AWS CLI --test option","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Retrieve the policy using the EC2 meta data service and use the IAM policy simulator","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using the CLI, create a dummy EC2 and delete it using another CLI call","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The --dry-run option checks whether you have the required permissions for the action, without actually making the request, and provides an error response. If you have the required permissions, the error response is DryRunOperation . Otherwise, it is UnauthorizedOperation . Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/ec2/terminate-instances.html"},{"question":"You application is deployed on EC2 and needs to access an internal API through API Gateway. Which authentication method will provide the easiest security?","answers":[{"text":"IAM permissions with sigv4","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Lambda Authorizer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cognito User Pools","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Although you can grant user access to the API created with API Gateway at the individual IAM user level, it is recommended that you grant access to Amazon API Gateway APIs at the IAM group level. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/knowledge-center/iam-authentication-api-gateway/"},{"question":"Which of these RDS features will force your developers to change their application code to fully take advantage of it?","answers":[{"text":"RDS Read Replicas","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS Multi AZ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"RDS backups","isCorrect":false},{"text":"RDS Maintenance Upgrades","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"RDS read replicas create new databases that have to be referenced by your application code Read more:  https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/USER_ReadRepl.html"},{"question":"You have enabled X-Ray integration with AWS lambda but can't see any data go through X-Ray. What's a likely reason of this?","answers":[{"text":"Fix the IAM Role","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Enable X-Ray sampling","isCorrect":false},{"text":"X-Ray only works with AWS Lambda aliases","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Change the security groups rules","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Create an IAM role with write permissions and assign it to the resources running your application. AWSXRayDaemonWriteAccess includes permission to upload traces. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/xray/latest/devguide/xray-permissions.html"},{"question":"A CloudFormation stack name must be unique across  ?","answers":[{"text":"the same region","isCorrect":true},{"text":"the same account","isCorrect":false},{"text":"all accounts","isCorrect":false},{"text":"doesn't need to be unique","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The stack name is an identifier that helps you find a particular stack from a list of stacks. A stack name can contain only alphanumeric characters (case-sensitive) and hyphens. It must start with an alphabetic character and can't be longer than 128 characters.Must be unique within a region"},{"question":"Your instance in us-east-1a just got terminated, and the attached EBS volume is now available. Your colleague tells you he can't seem to attach it to your instance in us-east-1b.","answers":[{"text":"EBS volumes are AZ locked","isCorrect":true},{"text":"EBS volumes are region locked","isCorrect":false},{"text":"He's missing IAM permissions","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can attach an available EBS volume to one of your instances that is in the same Availability Zone as the volume. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/EBSVolumes.html"},{"question":"All of a sudden, your CodePipeline breaks because it says it cannot find the target Elastic Beanstalk environment to deploy your application to. What should you do to find the root cause of this problem? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"Look in CloudTrail for a \"delete\" event in Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Look in IAM for Policy changes","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Look in CloudFormation for deletions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look in CodePipeline for changes","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look in S3 for access logs","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudTrail provides event history of your AWS account activity, including actions taken through the AWS Management Console, AWS SDKs, command line tools, and other AWS services. This event history simplifies security analysis, resource change tracking, and troubleshooting.Filter the CloudTrail data for delete events should help you in debugging the situation.Verify that appropriate policies have been attached to AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) users or groups for accessing the target Elastic Beanstalk environements. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/access_policies_testing-policies.html"},{"question":"Which hook step should be used in appspec.yml file to ensure the application is properly running after being deployed?","answers":[{"text":"ValidateService","isCorrect":true},{"text":"AfterInstall","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ApplicationStart","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AllowTraffic","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"ValidateService is the last deployment lifecycle event. It is used to verify the deployment was completed successfully. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/reference-appspec-file-structure-hooks.html#reference-appspec-file-structure-hooks-run-order"},{"question":"In CloudFormation, Stack-A exports some outputs that are referenced by Stack-B and Stack-C. In which order should you delete the stacks? ","answers":[{"text":"Stack B, then Stack C, then Stack A","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Stack A, then Stack B, then Stack C","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Stack A, Stack C then Stack B","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Stack C then Stack A then Stack B","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You could delete C, then B then A. A must come after B and C because the exported outputs are referenced there Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/using-cfn-stack-exports.html"},{"question":"You would like to control Elastic Beanstalk configuration dynamically as code. How can you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"Include config files in .ebextensions/ at the root of your source code","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Deploy a CloudFormation wrapper","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use SSM parameter store as an input to your Elastic Beanstalk Configurations","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use an AWS Lambda hook","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The option_settings section of a configuration file defines values for configuration options. Configuration options let you configure your Elastic Beanstalk environment, the AWS resources in it, and the software that runs your application. Configuration files are only one of several ways to set configuration options. Read more: see option_settings in https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/ebextensions.html"},{"question":"What security mechanisms are available out of the box and require no code change for Kinesis Streams? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"KMS encryption for data at rest","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Encryption in flight with HTTPS endpoint","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SSE-C encryption","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Client Side Encryption","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Envelope Encryption","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Server-side encryption is a feature in Amazon Kinesis Data Streams that automatically encrypts data before it's at rest by using an AWS KMS customer master key (CMK) you specify. Data is encrypted before it's written to the Kinesis stream storage layer, and decrypted after it's retrieved from storage. As a result, your data is encrypted at rest within the Kinesis Data Streams service. Also the HTTPS protocol ensures that data inflight is encrypted as well. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/streams/latest/dev/what-is-sse.html"},{"question":"Where must CloudFormation templates be stored in order to be loaded by CloudFormation?","answers":[{"text":"S3","isCorrect":true},{"text":"EBS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EFS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ECR","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"If you upload a local template file, AWS CloudFormation uploads it to an Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) bucket in your AWS account. If you don't already have an S3 bucket that was created by AWS CloudFormation, it creates a unique bucket for each Region in which you upload a template file. If you already have an S3 bucket that was created by AWS CloudFormation in your AWS account, AWS CloudFormation adds the template to that bucket. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/cfn-using-console-create-stack-template.html"},{"question":"Your application is using an Application Load Balancer. It turns out your application only sees traffic coming from private IP which are in fact your load balancer's. What should you do to find the true IP of the clients connected to your website?","answers":[{"text":"Look into the X-Forwarded-For header in the backend","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Modify the front-end of the website so that the users send their IP in the requests","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look into the X-Forwarded-Proto header in the backend","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The X-Forwarded-For request header helps you identify the IP address of a client when you use an HTTP or HTTPS load balancer. Because load balancers intercept traffic between clients and servers, your server access logs contain only the IP address of the load balancer. To see the IP address of the client, use the X-Forwarded-For request header. Elastic Load Balancing stores the IP address of the client in the X-Forwarded-For request header and passes the header to your server. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/latest/classic/x-forwarded-headers.html"},{"question":"You would like to deploy an application and define all the database authentication and authorization using IAM policies. Which database will be the best fit?","answers":[{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS MySQL","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":false},{"text":"MongoDB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Access to Amazon DynamoDB requires credentials. Those credentials must have permissions to access AWS resources, such as an Amazon DynamoDB table. You can use AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) to help secure access to your DynamoDB service. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/authentication-and-access-control.html"},{"question":"You would like to persist data of your EC2 instances so that the data can be detached and mounted to other instances if need be. Which technology should you choose?","answers":[{"text":"EBS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"FTP","isCorrect":false},{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) provides persistent block storage volumes for use with Amazon EC2 instances in the AWS Cloud. Each Amazon EBS volume is automatically replicated within its Availability Zone to protect you from component failure, offering high availability and durability. Read more: rhttps://aws.amazon.com/ebs/"},{"question":"Your company does not trust Amazon web services for their encryption services, but would like to store data encrypted in Amazon S3. Which method suits best these requirements?","answers":[{"text":"Client Side Encryption","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SSE-C","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SSE-S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SSE-KMS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can encrypt data client-side and upload the encrypted data to Amazon S3. In this case, you manage the encryption process, the encryption keys, and related tools. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/UsingEncryption.html"},{"question":"I have an ASG and an ALB, and I setup my ASG to get health status of instances thanks to my ALB. One instance has just been reported unhealthy. What will happen?","answers":[{"text":"The ASG will terminate the EC2 Instance","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The ASG will detach the EC2 instance from the group, and leave it running","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The ASG will keep the instance running and re-start the application","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"To maintain the same number of instances, Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling performs a periodic health check on running instances within an Auto Scaling group. When it finds that an instance is unhealthy, it terminates that instance and launches a new one.Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling creates a new scaling activity for terminating the unhealthy instance and then terminates it. Later, another scaling activity launches a new instance to replace the terminated instance. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/knowledge-center/auto-scaling-terminate-instance/https://docs.aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/ec2/userguide/as-maintain-instance-levels.html#replace-unhealthy-instance"},{"question":"What's the maximum data size that can be encrypted by KMS?","answers":[{"text":"4KB","isCorrect":true},{"text":"1MB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10MB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"16KB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can encrypt up to 4 kilobytes (4096 bytes) of arbitrary data such as an RSA key, a database password, or other sensitive information. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/kms/latest/APIReference/API_Encrypt.html"},{"question":"Which of the following services will not help you in understanding an authorization exception that happened when you ran a CLI command?","answers":[{"text":"CloudWatch","isCorrect":true},{"text":"IAM","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":false},{"text":"STS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudWatch helps only with metrics monitoring. The rest is relevant to help you debug authorization exceptions"},{"question":"Which function should you use to reference a CloudFormation parameter?","answers":[{"text":"!Ref","isCorrect":true},{"text":"!GetAtt","isCorrect":false},{"text":"!Param","isCorrect":false},{"text":"!Join","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The intrinsic function Ref returns the value of the specified parameter or resource.When you specify a parameter's logical name, it returns the value of the parameter.When you specify a resource's logical name, it returns a value that you can typically use to refer to that resource, such as a physical ID. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/intrinsic-function-reference-ref.html"},{"question":"You are looking for a pub sub solution where you send messages once and they are received by many different locations. Which technology helps you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"SNS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SQS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Kinesis","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lambda","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) is a highly available, durable, secure, fully managed pub/sub messaging service that enables you to decouple microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications.  Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/pub-sub-messaging/"},{"question":"You have a micro service architecture and find it hard to debug which microservice is failing when requests are done in your AWS infrastructure. Which service can help remedy the situation?","answers":[{"text":"X-Ray","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Systems Manager","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS X-Ray helps developers analyze and debug production, distributed applications, such as those built using a microservices architecture. With X-Ray, you can understand how your application and its underlying services are performing to identify and troubleshoot the root cause of performance issues and errors. X-Ray provides an end-to-end view of requests as they travel through your application, and shows a map of your application's underlying components. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/xray/"},{"question":"How can you easily encrypt your build artifacts coming out of CodeBuild?","answers":[{"text":"Specify a KMS key to use","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use an AWS Lambda Hook","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use the AWS Encryption SDK","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use In Flight encryption (SSL)","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: CloudFormation doc shows you can encrypt output in S3: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/aws-properties-codebuild-project-artifacts.html"},{"question":"You want to send customised email to your users. You should use","answers":[{"text":"SES","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SNS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SQS with Lambda","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Kinesis","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon SES) is a cloud-based email sending service designed to help digital marketers and application developers send marketing, notification, and transactional emails.  Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/ses/"},{"question":"You would like to use a service to create virtual machines in the cloud, and being able to fully control them in order to run your database software. Which service would you choose?","answers":[{"text":"EC2","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":false},{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) is a web service that provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. It is designed to make web-scale cloud computing easier for developers. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/"},{"question":"You have performed changes in your API gateway and these changes are not active. What should you do?","answers":[{"text":"Deploy to a stage","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Enable Custom Authorizer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use Stage Variables","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Check IAM permissions","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Each stage is a snapshot of the API and is made available for the client to call. Every time you update an API, which includes modification of methods, integrations, authorizers, and anything else other than stage settings, you must redeploy the API to an existing stage or to a new stage. As your API evolves, you can continue to deploy it to different stages as different versions of the API. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/how-to-deploy-api.html"},{"question":"You have created the S3 bucket named \"prod\", but the bucket creation failed. You triple checked and you are certain no other bucket in your AWS account exist with the name \"prod\". What's the most likely reason for this issue?","answers":[{"text":"Someone else in the world already created a bucket named \"prod\"","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You have the wrong IAM permissions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The bucket name is too short","isCorrect":false},{"text":"\"prod\" is a reserved bucket name","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Bucket names must be unique across all existing bucket names in Amazon S3. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/BucketRestrictions.html"}]}}]
a:[["$","meta","0",{"charSet":"utf-8"}],["$","meta","1",{"name":"viewport","content":"width=device-width, initial-scale=1"}]]
7:null
8:null
c:[["$","title","0",{"children":"v0 App"}],["$","meta","1",{"name":"description","content":"Created with v0"}],["$","meta","2",{"name":"generator","content":"v0.app"}]]
